At any rate,
I wonder where the hell he went...
…にしても ソラは いったい
どこ行ったのかしら？
What?!
Wait!
待てよ… 待て！ ソラ！
Wait! Sora!
Tsunade-sama!
綱手様！ うっ！
サクラか。
Sakura?
(綱手)これから
部隊長を集めてのミーティングだ。
I'm gathering the unit captains
for a meeting right now.
話は あとで聞く。
I'll talk to you later.
これは いったい…。
What the hell happened here?
Sora came after me.
(綱手)
ソラが 私を狙って ここに来た。
そんな…。
No way...
こんな大きな停電
今まで あったか？
Has there ever been this big
a power outage before?
単なる停電では
ないのかもしれんな。
It might not be just
a simple power outage...
大丈夫なのか？
う～ん…。
I wonder if things will be okay...
Oh!
Of course things will be okay!
(テウチ)でえじょうぶに
決まってんだろうが！
This village has the Hokage, after all!
この里には
火影様が いらっしゃるんだ。
Are you saying
you can't trust the Hokage?!
火影様を 信じられねえってのか!?
Stop your whining!
ガタガタ騒ぐんじゃねえ！
Th-That's right.
そ… そうだったな。
We have the Hokage with us!
オレたちには
火影様が いらっしゃるんだ。
(シカマル)ブレーカーじゃねえな。
It's not the circuit breaker.
Then we stand by in Area 3, right?
じゃあ ボクらは ３区で待機だね。
Yeah, as it says in
the contingency planning manual.
あぁ 緊急時対策マニュアルだな。
And the off-duty unit captains are
probably gathering at the mansion.
非番の隊長たちも
館に集合してんだろう。
If so...
ならば…。
ん？
フフフ… チョ～ うまい！
Tasty.
(チョウジ)準備完了！ これで
いつでも 全開でいけるよ！
Preparations complete!
Now I can go full throttle anytime!
Let's hurry, Shikamaru!
急ぐよ シカマル！
あぁ…。
Right...
(チョウジ)逃がさん！
You're not getting away!
(木ノ葉丸)どうしたんだ？ これ。
(モエギ)停電かしら？
What's going on?
Is it a power outage?
Oh, man...
I don't like the dark...
(ウドン)やだなぁ。
暗いの苦手だよ…。
(エビス)どうやら おかしなことに
なっているようです。
It appears something strange
is going on.
- What?!
(３人)え～!?
(コテツ)大門を閉めるぞ！
Close the main gate!
The hotline has been secured.
ホットラインが確保できました。
Now we should be able
to respond,
これで どこから敵襲があっても
対処できるはずです。
no matter where the enemy attack
comes from.
ご苦労。
Good work.
《これだけか。
This is it, huh...?
I allocated too many personnel
to the Hidden Rain border.
雨隠れとの里境に
人員を割きすぎたな》
(綱手)
みんなも見てきただろうが➡
As you have probably seen,
we're experiencing a power outage
現在 木ノ葉の里全体が
電力を絶たれ 停電に陥っている。
and the entire village is
without electricity.
原因が事故である可能性も
残ってはいるが➡
There is a possibility
it was caused by an accident.
But considering there has been
no contact from the power facility,
電力施設からの連絡がない
状況を考えれば➡
we should probably take action under
the assumption that this was deliberate.
人為的に起こされたものと考え
行動するべきであろう。
Therefore, as of this moment,
よって 現在より この里は
第二級警戒態勢に入る！
this village will enter
a level two state of alert!
Company Three will be dispatched
to the east, west and north gates.
第三中隊を
東 西 北門に振り分け➡
第二中隊は 大門へ。
Company Two will go to
the main gate!
Company One is assigned to check
on the situation at the power facility!
第一中隊は 電力施設の
状況確認にあたれ。
Asuma! You stay here.
(綱手)アスマ 残れ。
Don't overlook the slightest
unusual occurrence. Dismissed!
(綱手)各自 わずかな異変も
見逃すな。 散！
(綱手)ソラに 襲撃された。
ソラが!?
Sora attacked me.
Sora...?!
(綱手)幸い 事なきをえたが…。
Fortunately, the situation
didn't become serious...
Just a minute!
(アスマ)ちょっと待ってください！
You were attacked, Hokage-sama?!
襲撃って 綱手様をですか!?
ソラが!?
By Sora?!
Naruto is in pursuit.
今は ナルトが追っている。
(綱手)お前も すぐに向かえ。
You head after them immediately.
It may be difficult, but it's a fact.
Accept it.
受け入れがたくとも 事実だ➡
受け入れろ！
ソラを見つけ次第 拘束しろ！
As soon as you find Sora,
take him into custody.
Yes, ma'am!
(アスマ)はっ！
(イズモ)ん…。
(コテツ)どうした？
What is it?
(イズモ)今… 森が動いたような…。
I get... the feeling the forest
moved just now...
Is it an earthquake...?
地震か？
Travelers! We're sorry,
but the village is occupied right now.
旅のお人 すまないが 今 里は
とり込んでいる。
We cannot let anyone
in from the outside--
外部の人を
お入れするわけには…。
(フウカ)フフフ…。
うわぁ～！
(コテツ)なんだ!?
What's that?!
An enemy attack has been confirmed!
The main gate is under assault.
(シズネ)敵襲を確認
大門へと侵攻中！
(シズネ)
警備部隊が 戦闘に入りました。
The security units are now in combat.
始まったか…。
So it has begun, huh...?
フン…。
行け！
Go!
大門に近づけるな！
戦況は？
Don't let them get near the main gate!
What's the battle situation?
(ゲンマ)バカ！ うかつに近づくな！
You idiot! Stay away!
今より オレが指揮する。
I will take charge now.
遠距離攻撃に切り替える。
Shift to a long-range attack!
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
I haven't learned "sadness" yet.
kanashimi wa mada oboerarezu
And I'm just starting to grasp "misery".
setsunasa wa ima tsukami hajimeta
Even this feeling I hold towards you.
anata e to idaku kono kanjou mo
Is now turning into "words".
ima kotoba ni wakatteku
Waking up from the dream of this unknown world.
michi naru sekai no yume kara mezamete
I spread these wings and fly.
kono hane wo hiroge tobi datsu
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Knowing I'll find the answer,
tsuki nuketara
If I pierce through it.
mitsukaru to shitte
if I break free,
furikiru hodo
From that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Lockdown of Darkness
The enemy has not been stopped!
敵 停滞せず！
One kilometer to go
until the main gate!
大門まで １キロ。
警備部隊 なおも奮闘中。
ナルト…。
The security unit is engaged...
- Naruto...
- in a tough battle!
That way, huh...?
あっちか。
Sora!
ソラ！
Wait up, damn it...!
待てってば この！
Why did you attack Grandma Tsunade?!
なんだって 綱手のばあちゃんを
襲った!?
Leave me alone!
ほっとけ！
It's got nothing to do with you!
テメエには 関係ねえ！
なんだと!?
Oh yeah?! Of course it does!
関係ねえことあるか！
Barrier Defense Seal Jutsu!
結界門護封術。
(フエン)八門閉錠！
Eight-Gate Lock Up!
Wh-What...?!
な なんだ!?
Hey!
(イズモ)おい！
(コテツ)東門のほうにも…。
≪正門もだ！
There's one in the direction
of the east gate...!
And the west gate, too!
Tsunade-sama! What is this...?!
(シズネ)綱手様 これは…!?
Raise the level two
state of alert to level one!
第二級警戒態勢を
第一級に引き上げる！
待機中の者を
大門へと向かわせろ！
Send everyone on stand-by
to the main gate!
Yes, ma'am!
(伝達係)はっ！
Summon Shikamaru.
シカマルを呼べ。
Inform him of the situation and
have him draw up defense measures.
状況を伝えて
防衛策を立てさせろ。
Yes, ma'am!
はっ！
Sakura, you get ready to move out, too.
(綱手)
サクラ お前も 出る準備をしておけ。
(サクラ)はい！
Yes, ma'am!
What...?! What happened?
なんだ… 何が起きたんだ!?
They've... come...
(ソラ)来た… アイツらが。
Wait a minute, who's they...?
待てよ！ アイツらって!?
What do you know?!
お前 何を知ってるんだ!?
A barrier?!
防御結界!?
A barrier!
防御結界…。
なに!? どういうことだ!?
- What?!
- What's going on?!
The enemy... has put up... a barrier.
(エビス)敵は… ボウギヨケツカイを はれり。
A barrier?
(木ノ葉丸)ボウギヨケツカイ？
What kind of barrier?
(ウドン)何それ？
It's probably a "Defense Barrier".
(モエギ)防御結界じゃない？
Huh?
え？
言葉どおり➡
Oh... It's a barrier used for defense.
防御のための結界ってことよ！
It's used to defend
against enemy attacks,
(モエギ)敵の攻撃を防いだり➡
or as a wall to keep
the enemy from infiltrating!
壁となって
敵を侵入させないように➡
するためのもの。
Why would an enemy attacking
from the outside want to defend?
(ウドン)なんで 外から来た敵が
防御するの？
Defense aimed at us on the inside...
is weird.
中に向かっての防御って 変なの。
(エビス)変ではありません。
It's not weird.
中に向かっての防御 それは…。
Defense aimed at us...
That's...
In other words, we are...
(コテツ)つまり オレたちは…。
That's right. We've been trapped inside
the village by this barrier.
そうだ オレたちは この結界により
里内部に閉じ込められた。
Now what is it?!
今度は なんだってんだ!?
(フリド)我らこそは
火ノ国の義を通すため➡
The four of us have come here
on an unerring mission.
On behalf of the future strength
of the Land of Fire.
強固なる意志をもって
結ばれし４人。
今 その強き意志を伝えんがため
馳せ参じた。
We have come here to
enact our indomitable will.
しばし 聞かれよ。
Now, listen to what we have to say.
We have only one objective in mind.
多くは語らぬ。
我らが思いは ただひとつ。
And that is the glorification
of the Land of Fire
大名を中心とした 火ノ国の繁栄！
with the Feudal Lord as
its one and only king!
The king here in the Hidden Leaf Village
is a threat
されど 汝ら 木ノ葉の里にありし
もう一つの玉が。
to the true king of
the Land of Fire.
火ノ国の真なる玉を
脅かさんとしている。
We will not allow the existence
of two kings!
我ら 玉が 二つあるを許すまじ。
Don't you get it?
We're saying we don't need your Hokage!
わかんねえか！
オメエらの大将 火影が
いらねえって言ってんだよ！
なに!?
What...?!
There's no need for approval.
You guys will help us, either way.
(フリド)賛同する必要はねえよ。
どっちにしろ オメエらは
オレたちに協力するんだ！
死体になってな。
You'll help us by becoming corpses...
I learned that you can't get into
or out of a defense barrier...
(木ノ葉丸)防御結界って
入ることも出ることも➡
できないって教わったぞ コレ。
That's exactly right.
そのとおりです。
In this case, we should assume
the enemy got through the barrier
この場合 敵が特殊な術で 結界を
ぬけたと考えるべきでしょう。
using a special Jutsu.
今 木ノ葉の里は 封じ込まれ➡
Right now, the situation is that
the Hidden Leaf Village
has been confined
出入り自由なのは
敵だけだという状況です。
and only the enemy can come
and go as they please.
Now that we have allowed them
to infiltrate the village,
里への侵入を
許してしまった以上➡
we must shift to stage two of
the Sneak Attack Measures Manual.
奇襲対策マニュアルの第二段階へと
移行しなければなりません。
We're ready to fight anytime!
オレたちは いつでも 戦えるぞ コレ！
- Yeah!
No.
いいえ 反撃開始は➡
Initiation of a counterattack will come
after we have evacuated the civilians.
非戦闘員を
避難させてからです。
あなたたちは
迅速かつ 確実に➡
You guys, guide everyone quickly
to a safe location.
皆を安全な場所に
誘導してください。
This is your first A-rank mission.
(エビス)これは あなたたちにとって
初めてのＡランク任務です。
わかったぞ コレ！
Got it!
Dismissed!
散！
I'm counting on you guys.
I'll stall for time here.
頼みましたよ…。
私は ここで
時間を稼ぎましょう。
You can't just say whatever you want...
好き勝手 言いやがって！
(コテツ)五代目には 手を出させんぞ。
We won't let you get your hands
on the Fifth Hokage!
We must hold on
until the reinforcement units arrive...
《増援部隊がくるまでは
持ちこたえないとな》
フッ… フドウ！
Fudo!
ハッ！
(フドウ)土遁！
Earth Style!
有為転変！
Impermanence!
What?!
なにっ！ 下がれ！
Get back!
綱手様 準備できました。
Tsunade-sama, I'm ready.
(綱手)
直接戦闘が避けられない今➡
Now that we can't avoid direct combat,
１人でも 多くの負傷者を救うのが
医療忍者のつとめ➡
it's the duty of a Medical Ninja to save
as many of the injured as possible.
行け！
はい！
Go!
Yes, ma'am!
《完全とは いえないまでも
最善の手をつくしている。
Though not to perfection,
we've done just about all we can.
なのに何だ この胸騒ぎは…》
And yet, what is
this uneasiness I feel?!
次から次へと
なんてヤツらだ…。
It's just one thing after another...
These guys are awful...
(フリド)これぞ 土遁究極蘇生術！
死屍 土壌！
This is the ultimate Earth Style Jutsu!
Soil Bodies!
Come back to life, Shinobi corpses!
よみがえれ！ 屍の忍たちよ！
フハハハッ！
Our dead Shinobi are your opponents!
(フリド)我が死者の
忍衆が相手だ！
お前に オレの何がわかる！
What do you know about me?!
Nothing!
わかんねえよ！
アイツらって何だ。
Who are those guys?!
What did you do?!
お前 何をしたんだ？
(ソラ)先に オレを消そうとしたのは
木ノ葉のほうじゃねえか！
It was the Hidden Leaf who tried
to eliminate me first!
Grandma Tsunade would
never do something like that!
綱手のばあちゃんは
そんなことしねえ！
やったんだよ！
She did!
オレはやられる前に やるだけだ！
I just tried to get her before she got me!
≪(アスマ)ようやく追いついた。
I finally caught up.
アスマ先生！
Asuma-sensei!
You backstabber, Asuma!
裏切り者 アスマ!!
ソラ…。
Sora...
なぜ 火影様を狙った？
Why did you target the Hokage?
お前が復讐したいのは…。
The one you want revenge on is...
The one you want revenge on...
お前が復讐したいのは…➡
オレ。
触るな！
is me.
Don't touch me!
I just copied what you did!
オレは アンタのマネをしたんだよ。
The king you chose...
going so far as to kill my father...
アンタが父さんを殺してまで
選んだ玉を…。
玉!?
King...?!
This time I'll kill her!
今度はオレが
やってやるんだ！
What're you talking about?
I don't get it at all!
なに言ってんだ お前
わけわかんねえぞ。
No... it's the truth.
(アスマ)いや 本当のことだ。
ソラ…➡
Sora...
You called Tsunade-sama "king" just now,
didn't you...?
お前 今
綱手様のことを 「玉」と言ったな。
((フリド : 火ノ国に
２つの玉はいらん。
The Land of Fire doesn't
need two kings.
火影などという玉は
必要ではない。
The king known as the Hokage
is unnecessary!
国に玉は１つ 大名のみ！
A country only needs
one king, the Feudal Lord.
報告によると
今回の国境の襲撃に➡
According to the report,
the Hidden Rain was not involved
with the border attack.
雨隠れは
かんでおらん。
それより タツジの話では➡
More importantly, according to Tatsuji,
先日 火ノ寺付近の
隠し墓をあばいたと思われる➡
it seems he was assigned
on a mission the other day
to track and monitor
the group of four,
４人組を 追跡 看視の任務に
あたったそうだ。
thought to be the ones
who violated the hidden tombs
near the Temple of Fire.
お前たちが危惧したように➡
Just as you had feared,
it seems those four
その４人は
火ノ寺のあの少年➡
were trying to get their hands on
that Sora boy from the Temple of Fire.
(ソラを手に入れようと
しておったそうだ))
《つながりかけている…。
It's starting to make sense.
何かが…》
There's something...
チッ！ なんてこった！
No! This is terrible...!
What's the matter, Asuma-sensei?
どうしたんだ アスマ先生。
オレの推測が正しければ➡
If my guess is right,
this village is in deep trouble!
今 この里は
非常にまずい状態にある。
Don't rush!
Remain calm and focused.
押さないで！
落ち着いて急ぐんだコレ！
(アスマ)おそらく 里を
襲ってきている連中の狙いは➡
The objective of the group attacking
the village might be...
無差別殺りくだ！
なんだって!?
indiscriminate mass slaughter.
Say what?!
いい加減なことを言うな！
Cut the nonsense!
It all makes sense!
つながったんだ！
(アスマ)墓荒らしは なぜ
雷遁四人衆の遺体を狙った？
Why were the grave robbers
after the bodies of
four Lightning Style Shinobi?
それは 墓荒らしが
雷遁四人衆の術を➡
It's because they're familiar
with the power of the Jutsu
その力を
よく知るものたちだからだ。
of the four Lightning Style Shinobi...
そして その力を使って➡
And they hit upon the idea
of using that power
この里を一気に
せん滅する方法を思いついた。
to wipe out the entire village.
W-Wipe out...?!
せ… せん滅…!?
おい ソラ 本当なのか!?
Hey, Sora! Is that true?!
里をせん滅って…➡
Wiping out the village...
みんな
殺されちまうってことなんだぞ!!
That means everyone will be killed!
し… 知らねえ！
I don't know! I don't know anything!
オレは 何も知らねえ！
ソラ！
Sora!
(アスマ)
オレは 行かねばならん。
I must go.
一刻も早く止めねば
大変なことになる。
We must stop this
as soon as we can
or something terrible will happen, Naruto.
ナルト すまんがソラを頼む。
Sorry, but I leave Sora to you.
おう！
Right.
《ずっとあった違和感が
ようやく つながった。
That uncomfortable feeling I was
having all along finally makes sense!
ソラの話と
あの 「玉」という言い回し➡
What Sora was talking about,
and the word "king"...
間違いない。
There's no doubt about it!
The one carrying out the intentions
of that coup
この一連の事件の背後には➡
あのクーデターの遺志を
継ぐものがいる！》
is also behind this series of incidents!
"Red"
"Blue"
"White"
"Black"
Charging complete...
(キタネ)充電完了…。
Young people
iiijii na riyuu
I'll always accept your excuses
issai yurusu jakuhai
I summoned the rescue team too
resukuyuu tai mo yonde oita
So
dakara
Please kiss me please kiss me
puriizu kisu mii purizu kisu mi
All night
all night
The magic of a fallen angel or the silly pranks of a little demon
datenshi no mahou ka koakuma no chachi na itazura
Before it gets boring
tsuman naku nacchau mae ni
go and hurl
soore de houre
The bowling ball
bouringu booru
It's a strange existence
kibutsuhason zai nado
I know it already
shouchi no suke
It looks breakable...
kowaresou de
Clear the way with those sloppy emotions
tocchirakatta kanjou de kirihirake yo
It looks breakable
kowaresou de
Yet it's not our victory
kowasenai bokura no shouri
今回は オレたちのティーチャー
エビス先生を紹介するぞコレ。
Next Episode
What did you say?
The guys attacking us right now
are Shinobi from the Land of Fire?
エビス先生は
未来の火影候補生を➡
Yes. Judging from that
distinctive characteristic,
何人も育ててきたのよ。
there's no doubt
they're from the Kohaku Clan
(木ノ葉丸)オレも三代目火影
ジジイの孫として➡
who live in a village on the border.
But most of the Kohaku Clan
was supposed to have been killed
いろいろ 教わってきたぞコレ。
in a past attack.
(ウドン)特に チャクラコントロールの知識は
豊富で➡
Maybe the villagers
have been brought back to life
with some kind of Reanimation Jutsu.
ナルトのにいちゃんにも
修業をつけたんだ。
What a terrible thing to do.
Yes. It's unforgivable...
そんな先生にも
実は 弱点があって➡
They killed this many people just
to turn them into weapons!
昔 ナルトのにいちゃんの…。
うわ～!!
Revived Souls
Next time: "Revived Souls"
木ノ葉丸君 その話は絶対に
内密という約束ですぞ！
- Notable People in the Leaf Village!
え？ ハーレムの術で
鼻血ブーしちゃったこと？
Today, we're going to introduce
our teacher Ebisu-sensei!
こ 木ノ葉丸君！
声が大きいですぞ！
Ebisu-sensei has trained
several future Hokage cadets.
あ～ 腹へった
エビス先生 おごって。
And I also learned a lot as
the grandson of the Third Hokage.
な なんで私が!?
ハーレムの…。
さあ それではみんなで
一楽に行きましょう！
He is particularly knowledgeable
about chakra control...
(３人)やった!!
やれやれ…。
and trained brother Naruto as well.
As it happens, he has a weakness.
A long time ago, Naruto niii-chan's Har—
Konohamaru-kun. You promised to
keep that a secret, no matter what!
Huh?
You mean about how you got
a big old bloody nose from the Harem Jutsu?
K-Konohamaru! Not so loud!
Ohh, I'm hungry.
Buy us something, Ebisu-sensei.
Wha--?! Why should 1?
The Harem...
Okay, now let's all go to Ichiraku.
— Yes!
— All right!
Good grief...